<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Merriman Lab Notebook on MerrimanLab</title>
    <link>https://merrimanlab.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Merriman Lab Notebook on MerrimanLab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy;{year}, All Rights Reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2020 04:15:05 +0900</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://merrimanlab.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Getting Started</title>
        <link>https://merrimanlab.github.io/docs/getting_started/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2020 14:27:04 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://merrimanlab.github.io/docs/getting_started/</guid>
        <description>So you want to do some analyses, but don&amp;rsquo;t know where to start You have come to the right place!!
From a guide on how to run programs, to little tips and tricks to make your life easier, you will find it on this website.
For brand new lab members If you are brand new to this lab, read this page from top to bottom.
If you only want to know about a specific topic, you can search for things in the search bar at the top right hand corner, or alterntaively, you can look through each tab/section of this web site to find the right thing.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Before You Begin</title>
        <link>https://merrimanlab.github.io/docs/locuszooms/before_you_begin/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2020 00:36:39 +0900</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://merrimanlab.github.io/docs/locuszooms/before_you_begin/</guid>
        <description>Requirements and prerequisites Here is a list of requirements that you will need in order to run this tool (relatively) smoothly.
If you have access to the Department of Biochemistry server, you should have little to no problems to meet these requrirements.
Software You will need the following software to run this tool:
 Latest version of R Locus Zoom code from GitHub bcftools plink version 1.90 or later  Data You will need the following data to run this tool:</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How to generate LZ plot</title>
        <link>https://merrimanlab.github.io/docs/locuszooms/generating_single_locus_zooms/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://merrimanlab.github.io/docs/locuszooms/generating_single_locus_zooms/</guid>
        <description>Make Locus Zoom-like plots with your own LD matrix This script creates an R function to create regional Manhattan plots with points coloured according to LD and genes annotated beneath.
Input file format You will need at least two files to generate a Locus Zoom (LZ) plot: GWAS summary stats file, and a &amp;ldquo;gene&amp;rdquo; file.
The LD file can be generated on the fly, as long as you have access to the 1000GP reference data and the correct tools to calculate the LD (see Before you begin).</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Generate multiple LZ plots</title>
        <link>https://merrimanlab.github.io/docs/locuszooms/multiple_lz_plots/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://merrimanlab.github.io/docs/locuszooms/multiple_lz_plots/</guid>
        <description>Make multiple Locus Zoom plots This is a general guide and recommendation on how to make multiple Locus Zooms.
Loop the locus.zoom() call Probably the best way to make multiple Locus Zoom plots is to loop the function call to locus.zoom().
Inputs that change between different Locus Zoom plots are:
 SNP of interest/Gene of interest/Region of interest LD information of the region  Since the LD can be calculated on-the-fly, if you have a vector of SNPs/genes/regions of interest, you will be able to create a simple loop like so:</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>LZ with multiple data sets</title>
        <link>https://merrimanlab.github.io/docs/locuszooms/multi_pane_lz/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2020 15:45:55 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://merrimanlab.github.io/docs/locuszooms/multi_pane_lz/</guid>
        <description>Stack LZ plots from multiple summary data This page is a general introduction to add multiple &amp;ldquo;panes&amp;rdquo; to your LZ plots, using multiple summary data.
Why use multiple summary data? Often we want to overlay LZ plots of the same region from different summary data sets (e.g. different traits or comparison with cis-eQTL).
Rather than generating separate LZ plots for each summary data and compare them, we have provided a way to add as many &amp;ldquo;panes&amp;rdquo; of LZ as you like into a single output, where each pane shows the LZ plot of a particular region for the summary data sets you have provided.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Adding Annotations to VCFs</title>
        <link>https://merrimanlab.github.io/post/2021-09-21-vcf-annotation/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 21 Sep 2021 11:29:24 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://merrimanlab.github.io/post/2021-09-21-vcf-annotation/</guid>
        <description>The main consideration is to make sure that the reference resource matches the genomic build of your VCF. i.e. make sure you are using GRCh37 resources for a GRCh37 aligned VCF, or GRCh38 resources for a GRCh38 aligned VCF.
dbSNP A vcf from dbSNP can be used to annotate rsIDs into the ID column of a vcf. For instance the dbSNP v151 VCF can be downloaded here ftp://ftp.ncbi.nih.gov/snp/organisms/human_9606_b151_GRCh37p13/VCF/ - one key thing is make sure that you use the same genome build as your VCF that you want to annotate.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Working with UK Biobank</title>
        <link>https://merrimanlab.github.io/docs/ukbiobank-genomic-data/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://merrimanlab.github.io/docs/ukbiobank-genomic-data/</guid>
        <description>Load modules for processing VCFs These programs are usually all needed in order to do analysis with the UK Biobank genetic data.
module load bgenix/bgenix-1.1.8 module load bcftools/bcftools-1.11 The format for most analysis will follow this conversion:
bgen -&amp;gt; vcf -&amp;gt; bed/bim/fam (plink)
Extract and convert from bgen to VCF Extract region or SNP This command will extract out a region from the bgen file and turn it into a vcf</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>More on less</title>
        <link>https://merrimanlab.github.io/post/2020-10-20-less/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2020 13:37:24 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://merrimanlab.github.io/post/2020-10-20-less/</guid>
        <description>This post will cover some of the useful features in less that will let you look at any text-based document like a wizard!!
Scroll through page-wise As you may already know, you can use &amp;lt;space&amp;gt; to move one window forward in the document, but did you know there are ways to go back window-wise? Here is a table of some of the useful ways you can scroll through the document more efficiently (NOTE: ^ means press the &amp;lt;control&amp;gt; key with the following key):</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>GNU parallel</title>
        <link>https://merrimanlab.github.io/post/2020-10-19-parallel/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2020 13:22:48 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://merrimanlab.github.io/post/2020-10-19-parallel/</guid>
        <description>Intro GNU parallel (commonly referred to as just parallel) is a command line tool that allows you to run multiple independent tasks at the same time by using the available cores on a computer.
This post will cover:
 How to use parallel Some useful features provided by parallel  Basic usage The basic syntax of a parallel command is:
parallel &amp;quot;&amp;lt;command&amp;gt; {}&amp;quot; ::: &amp;lt;input&amp;gt; where &amp;lt;command&amp;gt; is the command you want to run in parallel for all the &amp;lt;input&amp;gt; you provide.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Beyond Software Carpentry Git</title>
        <link>https://merrimanlab.github.io/post/2020-10-16-beyond-swc-git/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2020 10:14:49 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://merrimanlab.github.io/post/2020-10-16-beyond-swc-git/</guid>
        <description>Intro Once you have finished Software Carpentry Git lesson, you should be able to do basic version controlling with Git. You would have learnt how to:
 Stage and commit your changes Make a remote GitHub repository Push and pull from your remote repository Solve merge conflicts  These skills are enough for you to get started with tracking and maintaining your own project, but once you start collaborating with others, you can run into trouble really quick.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A beginner&#39;s guide to making new posts with Hugo</title>
        <link>https://merrimanlab.github.io/post/2020-10-15-making-posts/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2020 11:42:39 +1300</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://merrimanlab.github.io/post/2020-10-15-making-posts/</guid>
        <description>What is Hugo? Hugo is a popular static site generator written in Go language. It&amp;rsquo;s static in the sense that the web pages do not change depending on who visits the site (for example, contents do not change for different user) &amp;ndash; all the contents displayed on the site are pre-defined. Given a bunch of markdown files, Hugo automatically convert those markdown files into HTML files that are ready for a web site.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Config files</title>
        <link>https://merrimanlab.github.io/post/config-files/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://merrimanlab.github.io/post/config-files/</guid>
        <description>Config files, sometimes referred to as dot-files, are files that you can make to customise the way a program behaves. Two such files you might like to create are .bashrc to customise how your bash looks and behaves, and .Rprofile to customise how R looks and behaves. Usually these files live in you home directory (~/) and because they have a &amp;lsquo;.&amp;rsquo; at the start are hidden from view by default but in bash you can view these hidden files with ls -A ~/.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Search for file under a directory</title>
        <link>https://merrimanlab.github.io/post/find_file_in_dir/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2020 08:50:27 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://merrimanlab.github.io/post/find_file_in_dir/</guid>
        <description>Search for file using &amp;ldquo;find&amp;rdquo; command Per man find:
 The find utility recursively descends the directory tree for each path
listed, evaluating an expression (composed of the &amp;ldquo;primaries&amp;rdquo; and
&amp;ldquo;operands&amp;rdquo; listed below) in terms of each file in the tree.
 Search for a file under a directory You can search for a file with specific name like so:
find /path/to/search -name &amp;lt;name of file/dir&amp;gt; The default path to search is the current directory .</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Remote Working</title>
        <link>https://merrimanlab.github.io/quickref/remote-working/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://merrimanlab.github.io/quickref/remote-working/</guid>
        <description>Merrimanlab Remote Working VPN access Credentials to use are your email/webkiosk
How to Install VPN:
Download Cisco AnyConnect from here: https://www.otago.ac.nz/its/services/network/otago038027.html
New process: https://otago.custhelp.com/app/answers/detail/a_id/2113
After you&amp;rsquo;ve gone through this process every time you want your home internet to pretend it is at uni open Cisco AnyConnect &amp;amp; tell it to connect to UO-VPN-SSL, then just use your internet like usual.
For students we will have to request your username be allowed VPN access, dependent on whether the uni devises another acceptable way for you to access our servers.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How is LD calculated?</title>
        <link>https://merrimanlab.github.io/docs/locuszooms/how_is_ld_calculated/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://merrimanlab.github.io/docs/locuszooms/how_is_ld_calculated/</guid>
        <description>On-the-fly LD calculation The Locus Zoom code calculates the LD of the region (+/-500kb) using the specified SNP (usually lead) as the reference variant to calculate the LD with other variants in the region.
This is done by calling external tools within R:
 bcftools to extract the relevant region from the 1000 Genomes reference VCF plink to calculate the LD of specified variant with all other variants in the extracted region  This is the default behaviour when you don&amp;rsquo;t provide the LD information to the LZ call.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>List of options</title>
        <link>https://merrimanlab.github.io/docs/locuszooms/list_of_options/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://merrimanlab.github.io/docs/locuszooms/list_of_options/</guid>
        <description>List of options Compulsory flags: One of snp, gene, or region must be specified to create the plot:
   Options Description Default value     snp specify the SNP to be annotated (you must also include ignore.lead = TRUE if choosing this option) NA   gene specify the Gene to make the plot around NA   region specify the chromsome region you want to plot (must be specified as c(chr, start, end) NA   data specify the data.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>cis-eQTL</title>
        <link>https://merrimanlab.github.io/docs/eqtl/cis-eqtl/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://merrimanlab.github.io/docs/eqtl/cis-eqtl/</guid>
        <description>Repo: https://github.com/MerrimanLab/QTL_pipelines
This pipeline runs a co-localisation analysis using a list of key SNPs, a GWAS results file, and the GTEx dataset.
bash cis_eqtl_pipeline.sh my_gwas.txt my_snplist.txt 1000000 8 </description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Data Formats</title>
        <link>https://merrimanlab.github.io/quickref/data-formats/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://merrimanlab.github.io/quickref/data-formats/</guid>
        <description>VCF Specification
https://vcftools.github.io/specs.html
PLINK PED/MAP or BED/BIM/FAM
Specification
https://www.cog-genomics.org/plink2/formats#bed
http://pngu.mgh.harvard.edu/~purcell/plink/data.shtml#ped
SAM/BAM Specification
https://samtools.github.io/hts-specs/
BED and GTF/GFF Specification
BED http://asia.ensembl.org/info/website/upload/bed.html
GTF/GFF http://asia.ensembl.org/info/website/upload/gff.html
FASTA/FASTQ Specification
FASTA https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/FASTA_format
FASTQ https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/FASTQ_format</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Reference Resources</title>
        <link>https://merrimanlab.github.io/quickref/reference-resources/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://merrimanlab.github.io/quickref/reference-resources/</guid>
        <description>Include name, location on server, link to source and when downloaded/created
Summary    Resource Version Created/Downloaded     1000 Genomes Project Phase3 September 2014/March 2017   Human Reference Sequence GRCh37 (build 37/hg19) tbc   dbSNP 137 tbc   GATK Resource Bundle b.37 tbc   1KGP Impute Panel Phase3 October 2014    Hosted shiny apps    Name URL     Merriman GTEx eQTL browser http://biochemcompute.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Training Resources</title>
        <link>https://merrimanlab.github.io/quickref/training-resources/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://merrimanlab.github.io/quickref/training-resources/</guid>
        <description>Current training resources for the lab
Novice/Intro: The Carpentries Software Capentry  Shell R Git/Github SQL  Data Carpentry  Data analysis and visualisation in R Best practice spreadsheets for use later in R  Custom made Merriman Lab R tutorial
 Intro lesson Stats lesson Programming lesson ggplot2 lesson  Additional: R  dplyr ggplot2 RMySQL Rmarkdown  </description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Genome Studio QC</title>
        <link>https://merrimanlab.github.io/docs/genome-studio-qc/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 21 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://merrimanlab.github.io/docs/genome-studio-qc/</guid>
        <description>This guide provides a comprehensive set of steps for the manual curation of genotype calls within Genome Studio. Genome Studio&amp;rsquo;s automatic clustering algorithms are reported to be accurate for ~ 99 % of SNPs. The other ~ 1 % need to be manually reviewed. This guide offers a consistent and logical approach and is aimed at reducing the workload where possible. The steps here are a combination of those published by Guo et al.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>New Lab Member</title>
        <link>https://merrimanlab.github.io/quickref/new-lab-member/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://merrimanlab.github.io/quickref/new-lab-member/</guid>
        <description>Orientation A (sort of) induction for new members to the lab to help them get up and running
Things that need to be sorted out for physical access  ID card loaded into door access system key (if applicable) Lab health and safety brief Dept health and safety  Comms  email  added to lab list lab meetings   invited to lab Slack merrimanlab.github.io  merrimanlab.github.io is a collation of many how-to&amp;rsquo;s for the lab as well and provides some reference material.</description>
      </item>
      
    
  </channel>
</rss>