<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>howto on MerrimanLab</title>
    <link>https://merrimanlab.github.io/tags/howto/</link>
    <description>Recent content in howto on MerrimanLab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy;{year}, All Rights Reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://merrimanlab.github.io/tags/howto/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Remote Working</title>
        <link>https://merrimanlab.github.io/quickref/remote-working/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://merrimanlab.github.io/quickref/remote-working/</guid>
        <description>Merrimanlab Remote Working VPN access Credentials to use are your email/webkiosk
How to Install VPN:
Download Cisco AnyConnect from here: https://www.otago.ac.nz/its/services/network/otago038027.html
New process: https://otago.custhelp.com/app/answers/detail/a_id/2113
After you&amp;rsquo;ve gone through this process every time you want your home internet to pretend it is at uni open Cisco AnyConnect &amp;amp; tell it to connect to UO-VPN-SSL, then just use your internet like usual.
For students we will have to request your username be allowed VPN access, dependent on whether the uni devises another acceptable way for you to access our servers.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Training Resources</title>
        <link>https://merrimanlab.github.io/quickref/training-resources/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://merrimanlab.github.io/quickref/training-resources/</guid>
        <description>Current training resources for the lab
Novice/Intro: The Carpentries Software Capentry  Shell R Git/Github SQL  Data Carpentry  Data analysis and visualisation in R Best practice spreadsheets for use later in R  Custom made Merriman Lab R tutorial
 Intro lesson Stats lesson Programming lesson ggplot2 lesson  Additional: R  dplyr ggplot2 RMySQL Rmarkdown  </description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>New Lab Member</title>
        <link>https://merrimanlab.github.io/quickref/new-lab-member/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://merrimanlab.github.io/quickref/new-lab-member/</guid>
        <description>Orientation A (sort of) induction for new members to the lab to help them get up and running
Things that need to be sorted out for physical access  ID card loaded into door access system key (if applicable) Lab health and safety brief Dept health and safety  Comms  email  added to lab list lab meetings   invited to lab Slack merrimanlab.github.io  merrimanlab.github.io is a collation of many how-to&amp;rsquo;s for the lab as well and provides some reference material.</description>
      </item>
      
    
  </channel>
</rss>