<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Documentation on MerrimanLab</title>
    <link>https://merrimanlab.github.io/docs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Documentation on MerrimanLab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy;{year}, All Rights Reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2020 04:15:05 +0900</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://merrimanlab.github.io/docs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Getting Started</title>
        <link>https://merrimanlab.github.io/docs/getting_started/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2020 14:27:04 +1200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://merrimanlab.github.io/docs/getting_started/</guid>
        <description>So you want to do some analyses, but don&amp;rsquo;t know where to start You have come to the right place!!
From a guide on how to run programs, to little tips and tricks to make your life easier, you will find it on this website.
For brand new lab members If you are brand new to this lab, read this page from top to bottom.
If you only want to know about a specific topic, you can search for things in the search bar at the top right hand corner, or alterntaively, you can look through each tab/section of this web site to find the right thing.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Locus Zoom</title>
        <link>https://merrimanlab.github.io/docs/locuszooms/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2020 00:36:39 +0900</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://merrimanlab.github.io/docs/locuszooms/</guid>
        <description>Description This is the documentation for the in-house Locus Zoom software, developed by Tanya, Matt, and Riku.
If you only need to generate a few plots, you may want to take a look at locuszoom.org instead.
Requirements and prerequisites Software You will need the following software to run this tool:
 Latest version of R Locus Zoom code from GitHub bcftools plink version 1.90 or later  Data You will need the following data to run this tool:</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>eQTL Pipeline</title>
        <link>https://merrimanlab.github.io/docs/eqtl/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:36:39 +0900</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://merrimanlab.github.io/docs/eqtl/</guid>
        <description></description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Working with UK Biobank</title>
        <link>https://merrimanlab.github.io/docs/ukbiobank-genomic-data/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://merrimanlab.github.io/docs/ukbiobank-genomic-data/</guid>
        <description>Load modules for processing VCFs These programs are usually all needed in order to do analysis with the UK Biobank genetic data.
module load bgenix/bgenix-1.1.8 module load bcftools/bcftools-1.11 The format for most analysis will follow this conversion:
bgen -&amp;gt; vcf -&amp;gt; bed/bim/fam (plink)
Extract and convert from bgen to VCF Extract region or SNP This command will extract out a region from the bgen file and turn it into a vcf</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Genome Studio QC</title>
        <link>https://merrimanlab.github.io/docs/genome-studio-qc/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 21 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://merrimanlab.github.io/docs/genome-studio-qc/</guid>
        <description>This guide provides a comprehensive set of steps for the manual curation of genotype calls within Genome Studio. Genome Studio&amp;rsquo;s automatic clustering algorithms are reported to be accurate for ~ 99 % of SNPs. The other ~ 1 % need to be manually reviewed. This guide offers a consistent and logical approach and is aimed at reducing the workload where possible. The steps here are a combination of those published by Guo et al.</description>
      </item>
      
    
  </channel>
</rss>